const cppQuestions = {
  "Chapter 1 - Fundamentals of Computer": [
    {
      question: "Meaningful and processed form of data is known as",
      options: ["Data", "Program", "Instruction", "Information"],
      answer: "Information",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is known as the brain of the computer?",
      options: [
        "Central Processing Unit",
        "Control Unit",
        "Arithmetic Logic Unit",
        "Monitor",
      ],
      answer: "Central Processing Unit",
    },
    {
      question:
        "CPU has three components. Which one of the following is the CORRECT option?",
      options: [
        "ALU, CU and ROM",
        "ALU, CU and RAM",
        "ALU, CU and Registers",
        "ALU, RAM and ROM",
      ],
      answer: "ALU, CU and Registers",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Name the character representation coding scheme developed in India and approved by the Bureau of Indian Standards (BIS).",
      options: ["ASCII", "ISCII", "EBCDIC", "UTF-8"],
      answer: "ISCII",
    },
    {
      question: "Write the full form of ASCII.",
      options: [
        "American Standard Code for Inter Communication",
        "Automatic Standard Code for Information Interchange",
        "American Standard Code for Information Interchange",
        "Advanced Standard Code for International Communication",
      ],
      answer: "American Standard Code for Information Interchange",
    },
    {
      question: "Write the full form of JPEG.",
      options: [
        "Joint Picture Encoding Group",
        "Joint Photographic Experts Group",
        "Joint Picture Experts Group",
        "Joint Pixel Encoding Group",
      ],
      answer: "Joint Picture Experts Group",
    },
  ],
  "Chapter 2 - Components of the Computer System": [
    {
      question:
        "The register in CPU that holds address of next instruction to be executed.",
      options: [
        "Memory Address Register",
        "Program Counter (PC)",
        "Instruction Register",
        "Accumulator",
      ],
      answer: "Program Counter (PC)",
    },
    {
      question: "USB stands for ...........",
      options: [
        "United System Bus",
        "Universal Standard Bus",
        "Universal Serial Bus",
        "Unified Serial Bus",
      ],
      answer: "Universal Serial Bus",
    },
    {
      question: "Write the full form of HDMI.",
      options: [
        "High Definition Multimedia Interface",
        "High Digital Multimedia Interface",
        "High Dynamic Media Interface",
        "High Definition Media Integration",
      ],
      answer: "High Definition Multimedia Interface",
    },
    {
      question:
        "______ memory is a small and fast memory between the processor and RAM.",
      options: ["Virtual", "Main", "Cache", "Flash"],
      answer: "Cache",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Mr. Rajmohan wants to buy a computer. He is an engineer by profession. He wants a device which can be used to ‘draw directly on screen’. Suggest him an input device.",
      options: ["Joystick", "Mouse", "Light Pen", "Trackball"],
      answer: "Light Pen",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the full form of MICR?",
      options: [
        "Machine Input Code Reader",
        "Magnetically Interpreted Code Reader",
        "Magnetic Input Character Recognition",
        "Magnetic Ink Character Recognition",
      ],
      answer: "Magnetic Ink Character Recognition",
    },
    {
      question: "Which printer is widely used as portable printer?",
      options: [
        "Inkjet Printer",
        "Dot Matrix Printer",
        "Thermal Printer",
        "Laser Printer",
      ],
      answer: "Thermal Printer",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Write an example of an operating system that is a free and open source software.",
      options: ["Windows", "macOS", "UNIX", "GNU/Linux"],
      answer: "GNU/Linux",
    },
    {
      question:
        "C++ uses the .................. language processor for translation.",
      options: ["Compiler", "Interpreter", "Assembler", "Loader"],
      answer: "Compiler",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Name the software that translates assembly language program into machine language.",
      options: ["Compiler", "Linker", "Assembler", "Interpreter"],
      answer: "Assembler",
    },
    {
      question: "Program written in HLL is known as",
      options: ["Byte Code", "Object Code", "Executable Code", "Source Code"],
      answer: "Source Code",
    },
    {
      question: "What is the full form of FSF?",
      options: [
        "Free Source Federation",
        "Free Software Foundation",
        "File Storage Format",
        "Foundation of Software Freedom",
      ],
      answer: "Free Software Foundation",
    },
  ],
};
